{"tossups": [{"question": "Elizabeth Tyler owned and operated a newspaper for this organization called<em> The Searchlight</em>, which ran articles written by Edward Young Clarke. The first national meeting of this group took place in 1867 at the Maxwell House Hotel in Nashville. This group was targeted in an 1871 Enforcement Act, and Nathan Bedford Forrest served as this group\u2019s first Grand Wizard. For ten points, name this cross-burning white supremacist group.", "answer": "<b> Ku Klux Klan</b> (or<b> KKK</b>)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "One of this man\u2019s daughters helped build fortresses in Stafford, Warwick, and Chester, earning her the nickname \u201cthe Lady of the Mercians.\u201d After this father of Aethlflaed and Edward the Elder won at Chippenham and Edington, he converted Guthrum to Christianity, baptizing Guthrum as his spiritual son. The Bishop Asser chronicled the life of, for ten points, what king of Wessex who ruled from 871 to 899 who, like Canute, was styled \u201cthe Great?\u201d", "answer": "<b> Alfred</b> the Great", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "One employee of this company, Gerhard Domagk, won a Nobel Prize but was arrested by the Nazis for contemplating accepting it. This company appointed Fritz ter Meer as its chair shortly after he finished his prison term for Nazi war crimes. Felix Hoffmann\u2019s work with this company included an acetylation of morphine, creating a compound that this company trademarked as heroin. For ten points, name this German pharmaceutical company whose chemists synthesized acetylsalicylic acid, or aspirin.", "answer": "<b> Bayer</b> AG", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "Adi Dassler convinced this \u201cBuckeye Bullet\u201d to wear his Schuhfabriks, marking the first sponsorship of African-American male athletes. Leni Riefenstahl\u2019s film<em> Olympia</em> records one of this man\u2019s victories. A snubbed handshake between this man and a world leader was lauded as a strike against Aryan supremacy, but this man was also snubbed by FDR when he returned home. For ten points, name this athlete who won four track and field gold medals at the 1936 Berlin Olympics.", "answer": "Jesse<b> Owens</b>", "metadata": "Trash - Trash"}, {"question": "To produce this good, a heating source called an arch is used. A precursor to this good called gorosoe is produced in towns like Hadong in South Korea. In 2012, Teriak Caron and Inouk Caron were arrested in conjunction with the heist of over 6 million pounds of this good from a warehouse in Quebec. Late winter marks sugaring season, which is the best time to harvest this good\u2019s precursor through tapping. For ten points, name this sweet foodstuff whose American production has traditionally been dominated by Vermont maple forests.", "answer": "<b> maple syrup</b> (prompt on syrup alone before \u201cmaple\u201d is read) Page 1", "metadata": "Trash - Trash"}, {"question": "During this man\u2019s presidency, a protest against a tax on dwelling-houses was led by the auctioneer John Fries. This first U.S. ambassador to Holland wrote about checks and balances in his<em> Thoughts on</em> <em>Government</em>. The Kentucky and Virginia Resolutions were written in opposition to this President\u2019s set of anti-immigration laws, the Alien and Sedition Acts, whose unpopularity led this man to lose his re-election bid to Thomas Jefferson. For ten points, name this founding father and second U.S. President.", "answer": "<b> J</b>ohn<b> Adams</b> (prompt on Adams; do not accept or prompt on John Quincy Adams)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "This group\u2019s newspaper was the Final Call, and the Italian Muslim Association issued a fatwa against this group because it fails to advocate prayer five times a day. One member of this group taught his followers about the \u201cMother Wheel,\u201d an alleged UFO found in the book of Ezekiel. Wallace Fard founded this group, which holds that all races were creations of the scientist Yakub. Louis Farrakhan currently leads, for ten points, what predominantly African-American religion whose members included the converted Cassius Clay and Malcolm X?", "answer": "<b> Nation of Islam</b>", "metadata": "Religion - Religion"}, {}, {"question": "This man travels to visit a man and his wife in a 1998 play by Michael Frayn, who claimed all the spoken dialogue in the play was said by their real-life counterparts. Heinrich Himmler derisively called this man a \u201cwhite Jew\u201d in an affair caused by the question of who should succeed this man\u2019s teacher, Arnold Sommerfeld. Along with Pascual Jordan and Max Born, this man developed a matrix formulation of quantum mechanics. In 1927, this man stated that the momentum and position of a particle cannot be known simultaneously. For ten points, name this scientist who formulated a namesake uncertainty principle.", "answer": "Werner<b> Heisenberg</b>", "metadata": "Philosophy - Philosophy"}, {}, {"question": "The Twenty-Six Martyrs were crucified in this city in 1597 for being Christians. The fan-shaped island of Dejima in this city\u2019s harbor was the only trading post where foreigners could trade during the sakoku period. Kokura was the original target for one attack on this city, but cloud cover led to this city being targeted instead. Charles Sweeney commanded the B-29 Superfortress Bockscar that devastated this city on August 9, 1945. For ten points, name this Japanese city that was attacked with the \u201cFat Man\u201d bomb, the second atomic bombing of World War II.", "answer": "<b> Nagasaki</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "One newspaper campaigned against this leader, saying \u201cStop the waste of our nation, for your job, your children, and your future!\u201d, but this leader defeated Michael Foot anyway. Geoffrey Howe turned on this leader, who resigned after pressure from Michael Heseltine. This leader\u2019s adoption of the Community Charge prompted the Poll Tax Riots. This leader succeeded James Callaghan following the Winter of Discontent, and her strict education cuts led to the nickname \u201cMilk Snatcher\u201d. For ten points, name this first female Prime Minister of Great Britain.", "answer": "Margaret<b> Thatcher</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "An equestrian statue by this man was modified to depict Marcus Curtius due to the displeasure of its original subject, King Louis XIV. He created several busts of Pope Urban VIII, as well as a piece depicting included the Nile, Danube, Ganges, and Rio de la Plata. He made a piece for the Cornaro Chapel in which an angel is points a golden spear at the title Carmelite nun. For ten points, name this Italian Baroque sculptor of<em> The Fountain of the Four Rivers</em> and<em> Ecstasy of St. Theresa</em>.", "answer": "Gian Lorenzo<b> Bernini</b>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Visual Fine Arts"}, {}, {"question": "Durad Brankovic prevented Skanderbeg\u2019s army from participating in a battle at this location, which was fought by Janos [YAHN-oash] Hunyadi after his previous defeat at Varna. Vuc Brankovic fled another battle at this location in which both commanders, Sultan Murad I and the Prince Lazar, were killed. That battle on the Field of Blackbirds shares its name with a country whose independence war resulted in NATO bombing Yugoslavia. For ten points, name this country, whose Albanian majority declared independence from Serbia in 2008.", "answer": "Republic of<b> Kosovo</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "This man gained the respect of his enemies after stopping a massacre at Fort Meigs. The appearance of a comet helped this man helped convince his troops of victory, since his name meant \u201cshooting star.\u201dThis ally of Henry Proctor had earlier worked closely with Isaac Brock in the siege of Detroit, and his support swelled following the New Madrid Earthquake. Following his death at the Battle of the Thames, his confederation of tribes fell apart. For ten points, name this Native American chieftain who fought alongside the British in the War of 1812.", "answer": "<b> Tecumseh</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "<b>The purpose of this entity was greatly altered following the signing of the \u201cOld Covenant.\u201dThis body was founded at Thingvellir, the \u201cassembly field.\u201d In ancient times, its 39 leaders</b> <b>met around the (+)</b> <b>Logberg, or Law Rock. This body, which was formerly composed of</b> <b>leaders called godars, is currently dominated by the Progressive and Independence party. It was briefly relegated to being a court of law during (*)</b> Danish rule. Einar Kristinn Gudfinnsonn is the speaker of this body, the oldest parliament in the world. For ten points, name this Icelandic governmental institution.", "answer": "<b> Althing</b> (prompt on Icelandic government before mentioned)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b>Pierre Dorsaz saved one man performing this action, then asked for the mule that man was riding on as a reward. Alexander Suvorov declared \u201cthe Russian eagles have outflown the Roman eagles\u201d after performing this action, which was forced by the Second Battle of (+) Zurich. One instance of this action failed to relieve the Siege of Genoa, but resulted in the Treaty of Lun\u00b4eville after the Battle of Marengo. That instance of this action saw the Army of the Reserve led (*) </b> through the Great Saint Bernard Pass by the first Consul of France. For ten points, Napol\u00b4eon performed what action, which involved leading an army over a Swiss mountain range?", "answer": "<b> crossing the Alps</b> (accept descriptions)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>The sitting vice president denied knowledge of this event, stating that he was \u201cout of the loop,\u201d although he later noted that \u201cmistakes were made.\u201d Manucher Ghorbanifer came</b> <b>close to accidentally stopping this event thanks to his extortionate (+)</b> <b>price quotes. This</b> <b>event violated the Boland Amendment, and it was investigated by the Tower Committee, which led to indictments for Caspar (*) </b> Weinberger and Oliver North. For ten points, name this scandal in which arms were illegally sold to a Middle Eastern country to fund the Nicaraguan enemy of the Sandinistas.", "answer": "<b> Iran-Contra</b> scandal Page 9", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b>One character created by this author gives out sums of money to anyone who needs it from a Foundation named after his father, an Indiana Senator. Another of this man\u2019s novels earned him a master\u2019s degree in anthropology from the University of Chicago and takes</b> <b>place in the fictitious Republic of (+)</b> <b>San Lorenzo. This author of</b><em><b> God Bless You, Mr.</b></em> <b>San Lorenzo. This author of</b><em><b> God Bless You, Mr.</b></em> <em><b>Rosewater</b></em><b> and</b><em><b> Cat\u2019s Cradle</b></em><b> wrote about a character who becomes (*)</b> <em><b>Rosewater</b></em><b> and</b><em><b> Cat\u2019s Cradle</b></em><b> wrote about a character who becomes (*)</b> \u201cunstuck in time,\u201d experiencing the firebombing of Dresden multiple times. For ten points, name this author who created the character of Billy Pilgrim in<em> Slaughterhouse Five</em>.", "answer": "Kurt<b> Vonnegut</b>", "metadata": "Literature - American Literature - Long Fiction"}, {}, {"question": "<b>This man suffered a serious setback when his subordinate, Walter Thiel, was killed and his workplace destroyed during Operation Hydra. This member of the Peenem\u00a8unde group</b> <b>was lauded in propaganda for creating new (+)</b> <b>\u201cwunderwaffes\u201d [voon-der-vah-fehs] by</b> <b>Joseph Goebbels. After the war, this man was headquartered in Huntsville, as Operation (*) </b> Paperclip brought him to the United States. The phrase \u201cI aim for the stars but, sometimes, I hit London\u201d was used to mock, for ten points, what German rocket scientist who developed the V-2?", "answer": "Wernher<b> Von Braun</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b>Master of disguise Izzy Einstein enforced this policy with the phrase \u201cThere\u2019s sad news here.\u201d It was also enforced by an incorruptible police force called \u201cThe (+) Untouchables\u201dled by Eliot Ness. Ness was tasked with ending Al Capone\u2019s control over Chicago\u2019s (*) </b>speakeasies. This policy was established via a Constitutional amendment ratified in 1919. For ten points, name this thirteen-year period of American history during which alcoholic beverages were forbidden.", "answer": "<b> Prohibition</b> (accept descriptions of the<b> ban</b>ning of<b> alcohol</b>ic beverages before mentioned) Page 10", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}], "bonuses": []}